So. Hello.
Hello. Welcome to the Latent Space.
My name is Katie Roberts.
I've been hosting on this stage today.
And right up next we've got Christopher Batey.
He works for as a CTO for Core Engineering Consulting Group.
And his talk is building product teams in the age of AI.
What we had to relearn every quarter.
Thanks. Thanks very much.
Caleb.
Yeah.
Okay.
So what I'm going to go.
Through is and if everything that we've learned
well, not everything, but certainly the, the,
the important things for building a product team in the age of AI.
So I work for Core Engineering Consulting Group,
and there's a keyword in there called consulting.
And in historically, we have been a consulting firm
in the domain of platform engineering and continuous delivery.
And if I if I see where we're at about two years ago, the majority of the engineers
at our organization would be at client sites, and we would only work
with large enterprise clients across media, finance, healthcare.
And we do two types of things.
We'd do advisory, so we'd help them.
We'd look at their continuous delivery
practices, digital transformation, building developer platforms,
and we'd give them advice on how to how to move forward.
And then we provide the engineers to go in and help do that thing if needed.
They can either take that and do that, or we could go in and help them.
And for the people who've worked at this type of knowledge based consultancy,
you know, the way that you,
you operate as a business is because you're a specialized in your domain,
which in our experience is platform engineering and continuous delivery.
You can normally add quite a lot of value because the engineers at the our
clients, while they're focusing on media or finance or healthcare.
But anyone who's tried to
scale an organization like this beyond a handful of engineers knows
that it's really, really hard because as you get more and more people,
it's really hard to keep your edge about being experts in that domain.
So you start to build systems for it.
And two years ago, this is what our systems look like.
So we don't want to train our engineers internally.
And the actual type of training it would be information on wikis.
It would be decks we'd run workshops, we'd do bootcamps with our engineers.
The other thing we had was a lot of text and spreadsheet based knowledge
on what good looks like in platform engineering and continuous delivery.
So it would be what features does a development platform have?
What how?
What type of testing are you doing in your path to production?
And we'd have quick ways of evaluating whether what people were doing
based on where they'd want to get to.
And then the third was like reference material.
So because we kept on building the same type of thing over and over again
at our clients, then we'd end up with roadmaps, predefined roadmaps
with epics and milestones and tasks for building certain types of things.
And that naturally led to reference implementations.
So for key features that we kept building and building again for different clients,
we'd end up with some kind of reference implementation we could bring in.
That is not where we're at today, though.
And, you know,
the premise of this talk is we probably wouldn't be
where we're at today without AI.
So if I take the training that used to be wikis, decks and workshops,
that right now is an internal interactive training platform.
So all the engineers are going to join our company.
They go and learn about continuous delivery and platform engineering.
They learn about a concept,
say versioning and promotion or different types of testing.
So you can release your software more quickly.
And then we have software which provisions them
a realistic environment to try that skill out.
So your training is normally made up of like showing something, telling something.
But now we have an interactive training platform that can do the thing.
So like an example would be it automatically provisions them a GitHub
repository, an environment like a namespace and Kubernetes
plus say a cloud account, and then the software
running in the background, which is checking that they've done
the thing, you know, like deployed, just deployed an immutable version artifact.
The processes, which used to be lots of wiki pages and spreadsheets
and all engineers love wiki pages and spreadsheets,
is now like an interactive tool,
which all of our engineers use to track the maturity
of various things that we are specialists in all of our all of our clients.
So it could be security,
it could be security, could be application architecture for continuous delivery.
It could be the types of testing or promotion
you did and the reference implementation.
So the roadmaps and developer platform features,
well we still use those with enterprise clients, but we use them
to build an off the shelf developer platform for like smaller companies.
So rather than just working
with huge companies, we now work with small companies
where we can install this into their cloud provider,
and they can get some of the benefits
that the big companies would normally spend
millions and millions of pounds building internally.
And just to add on some more fun, that internal tool has become a SaaS.
So now our actual enterprise clients
can log in themselves and reasonably complex to to do that.
And then the product which we built, which is for small to medium enterprises,
well, we are actually its best customer because when we built it,
I wasn't thinking we're going to use this
to build all of our products, but now we do.
So we use that as a as a customer.
And just to give you a flavor of what this looks like,
well, one of the managed services which we which we host, this is a margin.
This is what I mean by insights.
So being able to quickly
see the maturity of various stages of the path
to production and across lots of different components,
and then the developer platform, this is the user interface for it,
where I can see which version of which my components is in different
environments as part of the path to production.
That's not that interesting.
That's just what we build.
I think the important thing is, is we're building two types of systems, right?
There's systems which manage very sensitive data.
If any of our clients were to any of the data which we have
in the first system that I described would be leaked or exposed in
some way, that would probably be the end of our relationship with that client.
And then the other product manages people's production environment.
So the impact of it going wrong is pretty severe.
So that's kind of the impact I want to talk about.
I'm talking about building a product team, which is going to manage a system
where it really matters
if it goes wrong, rather than like working on lots of other small projects,
which might be like websites with basic, basic functionality.
And that is in the context of everything we're hearing today in an industry,
and especially on social media, that we're rapidly approaching a world
where software no human has ever seen reaches production.
And I don't think this is hypothetical anymore.
And I'm definitely not talking about our side projects
or the like, one person businesses where they're quickly idea
and putting something in production. I think that's totally fine.
I'm talking about the systems which have your credit card details,
or they manage or your personal or healthcare data.
And this actually starts to scare me, right?
Because code can do anything with the data it has access to.
And if we're not looking at that code, that could do anything.
So certainly if my bank started doing this or my healthcare
company started doing this, I'd start to be pretty scared.
And I think some of the optimism optimism is real, right?
Everyone is kind of worked in this area for the last
24 months, especially the last nine months, the last 12 months.
AI is absolutely fantastic at writing code, right
when we started building these products, it was 50 over 50.
Whether the code would compile with these tools right now, it's going to compile.
It's probably going to work, and I'm more just spending time refining how it works.
So it is pretty amazing.
That said,
I don't think it's a good at other parts of the software delivery lifecycle.
So my question for you to think about
is, is writing code the hardest part of software engineering?
Because I definitely think that's the best thing right now that AI is good at.
And is software engineering really the hardest part of a successful
digital product and building
and building products, by which I mean like adopted features in production
that potentially generate revenue or whatever impact.
And I wanted to get I'm sure this isn't going to be
the only time you're going to be asked this today.
And I've seen this been asked
to quite a few conferences up until now, but I wanted to get an idea of
who's in the audience.
So for the code or digital product that you're working on,
that is what you're paid for.
I know we've all got
like at least 20 side projects recording on at the weekend, so not those.
What percentage of your code is currently written by AI?
And it's good to exercise.
So I'm going to get you to put your hand up.
Who here has less than 10% of the code written by AI for their real system.
So we've got one two any like full manual coders?
I didn't put zero as an option.
No no no no.
But under 10%.
What about under 50%.
So I'd say maybe 20%.
What about 90?
Most under 9,100%.
There's quite a few of the 100%. We're there.
I would say for us we're at 90 to 100%.
It's very, very rare in my company that any of the engineers
actually writing code.
I would say, though, that this is a vanity metric which people like to talk about,
because out of all that code, and if I look in my main
branch of any of our products, it's all written by now,
but how much of it was written without any human intervention
with software engineers like using critical thinking?
And I think the answer is probably like zero zero for 30.
Certainly, certainly.
I would say that
my experience of the last of the last year or so is AI is an amplifier.
So for the things that we did really well as a company,
it allows us to do it much quicker, right, for the things that we did really badly,
which we're trying to improve on.
And many of the like the topic of this talk,
then all it's done is amplify the things that we didn't do so well.
And for me, it's really enabled, like delivery focused engineers.
So people are really focusing on getting working software adopted in production.
It's really like being the game changer for us.
And my company certainly wouldn't be in the position it is right now
if AI didn't exist, because we couldn't have afforded
probably to hire a ten person product team to two years ago.
What about this question, which is slightly more controversial?
I'm going to see if we get to the same kind of answers.
So what?
The center of your code goes to production without humans ever seeing it.
So the person prompting the agent,
the automatic agent ending workflow, or maybe someone doing a review after that.
So does anyone have no code going to production?
Actually that's more than 50. That's 50%.
So I'm pretty happy with that one actually.
Does anyone get all the way to 100% where not a single human
sees the code which goes into production?
Is anyone at the other extreme it gives me?
Oh, there's a couple.
There's a couple.
Well, it's good, it gives me hope. We're here.
I would love to say actually 0%, even though like we're massively adopting
AI and we're massive at my company, I just couldn't guarantee it.
So I went with the less than 10%.
And I think the thing which
like worries me more and more important is what percentage of your code already,
what percentage of your system goes to production
without a human understanding and understanding it?
And to think about that, I wanted to like, dig into
and start to think about what we actually do to build a digital product.
So we produced code for a long time, digital assets,
and we end up with a product.
And the producer is up until recently been a human
flesh and blood product owners, QAS developers.
It was it was a team.
And the thing we produce is a digital asset, right?
It's code. It's an artifact.
It's verification. It could be the testing.
It could be the monitoring and alerting. It could be the documentation.
So this is where we're at a couple of years ago
now the production of our digital product is very much becoming a black box
to all of us. Right.
So you could be using some agent workflow.
You could be using Codex, or Claude Code, some kind of autonomous agent.
But I'm not too worried about this. Right.
Because I'm still producing my digital product,
which I own at the end of it, and I understand it.
But of course, it's a slippery slope which we're all being pushed into doing,
you know, go faster, go faster, go faster.
So at some point it becomes this where we don't understand really
how it's being produced and we don't actually understand
the thing that's being produced.
But don't worry,
because obviously the answer to this is we look at the verification.
Right?
So as long as you understand
the black box tests of the thing now no longer understand, it's okay.
If I understand, say,
my acceptance tests, my functional test, it's doing the right thing,
then everything is okay.
But when people do this, what I find is it quickly becomes this,
then quickly becomes this, then quickly becomes this.
And the no one stands a thing.
What's going on?
So my first tip, and the thing which we've tried to work on recently inside
my organization, is to not delegate our systems thinking to agents.
So I'm not going as far to say as everyone understands every single line of code,
but let's not delegate systems thinking to agents.
So I want to give you a concrete example of a change in our delivery process
that we made recently.
So here's a very simplistic architecture diagram of one of our managed
managed services.
We've got back private backends like training pulse insights teams.
We've got a public front end and some kind of authentication service.
What it does doesn't really matter,
but this is something our clients just log into, right.
They have no idea how it's implemented.
And if they ever knew how it was implemented, it's
probably because we, you know, we broke it somehow.
On the other side is something we deploy actually at our clients.
And this is an intentional system design because it is it has access to their data,
and it does lots of processing where the clients
would not want that data to leave their premise, their, their network.
So it has its own front end now.
Lots and lots of features.
Keep on getting requested that require this connection, right?
Some of the functionality we've got in the managed managed service
and then combining it somehow with the client side
agent, which is running and collecting and processing data.
Now, I could just describe the feature I want, the feature I want
which would combine this,
and I'm pretty confident that our agentic workflow would build it.
And then maybe a pull request is going to land, which is maybe
7000, 7000 changes.
And then what would I be reviewing it for?
Well, I first want to reviewing it for the systems thinking.
So here's some questions which I just threw together
about what I'd want to know about this change.
How does the client side connect to the manage?
What does it connect to?
How does it and authorize?
Because this is a client side component.
Talking to a multi-tenant managed service, what parts of the managed service
are exposed to the internet?
We're very careful about not exposing things.
You know, do we ever share an API which is used by a human usable front end
versus like an agent system?
What data can pass from the client and the managed?
What data? Compassion manages the client.
There are different deployment mechanisms, right?
We do continuous delivery virtually every commit for the managed service.
But the client side, that means that we need
we need to do something on our client.
And maybe that might get updated once a week because it's deployed
deployed to their systems.
So that's the type of thinking I definitely want to keep
into the engineers that I work with.
So one thing we do now is when we're
planning whatever work we're going to do in the next week
is if
we think there's a system level decision that always comes as a completely separate
pull request in something called an architectural decision record.
If you've not come across those, Google them.
It's about documenting your technical decisions
along with your code so that you can.
Someone can quickly learn
why we made the decision, so we don't keep on discussing them again.
And we've always used ADR, or at least for a very long time.
And when we first adopted
agentic development, all of the agents loved writing aids.
They were very good at seeing that we had ADRs.
So they wrote more ADRs, and our ADR has got longer and more verbose.
Another single human understood them, which completely defeated the point
of having them.
So what we did is we said from now on, we're going to start with the ADR.
I, me as a human, I'm going to spend a lot of time reviewing it.
I want diagrams, I want them to be visual so I can I can understand them.
And then humans reviewing them can really put a lot of effort
into reviewing those architectural decision records.
And once you've got those agents are really, really good
at reviewing
implementations against well-structured architectural decision records,
not only when you eventually land
the implementation, but all of the follow up requests then.
Because one thing
I don't think humans are good at is keeping all of those aids in your head,
and then
subsequent pull requests, which subtly, perhaps change your system architecture.
You might not realize that something's happened.
Something's happening like a new API is exposed.
But what we actually do is have the ads constantly reviewed
against all of the poor requests that come in.
So that's kind of my first tip about not delegating systems thinking to agents.
The next thing I wanted to dig a bit deeper into is have a real
think about the dependency you want to put on the producer of your digital product.
So if we go back to this diagram and we've accepted that,
maybe we don't understand how agent workflows actually produce code.
If we were to break it down a bit more.
So I'm breaking down the producer box into three things.
We've heard the first one, I've called it interface,
but in most places we'll call it harness, like in the keynote.
So there's an interface for how you do that, right?
That could be Claude Code. It could be Claude Code.
It could be Codex.
It could be some automatic workflow based off your, your your GitHub issues.
Then you've got the thing which is hosting your model. Right.
So that could be directly it could be the Anthropic API,
but you could be hosting your own.
You could be using a third party which reached between them.
And then you've got your model.
So really your black box is made up of three things that you don't understand.
It's called code.
It's an API which perhaps at 330 on an afternoon stops working.
Anyone experienced that? Does anyone feel the most productive?
Once the Americans wake up and and make the Anthropic APIs.
Go down?
And then you've got the model, which obviously you don't understand.
I'm not saying you only see on this day, if anyone wants to explain
how opus works to me, I'm very happy to hear it.
So we can choose not to be quite so coupled to that workflow.
We can use a harness which is open source.
What's the benefit of that?
You know, when Anthropic goes down, I just switch to OpenAI
with a single command and I carry on.
I obviously get different results.
Every model gives you different results, but it's a good to have the way
that you're building your digital product be able to flip between providers.
You could go as far as to hosting the models themselves.
That limits the models.
You could do use something like so,
and then if you want, you could use a model
with open weights or at least an open source way, the way you that's trained.
I don't think any of that is that important, apart from being able
to switch between providers very quickly.
If you've got a production outage and suddenly at the same time, let's say
your favorite AI provider does,
and the only way your engineers can debug production is with that model.
Good luck.
I think it's more important that you end up understanding the product
that's developed, because they can't take that away from you.
I don't think it's produced that.
It's your intellectual property.
It's a whole different ball game, though.
If you build interactions into your product,
then then you've got another black box inside your black box.
So vendor lock in is fine as part of your development process.
Maybe we've all done it.
Cloud providers, roles, all sorts of things, but make it a conscious choice
in your organization and understand the consequences of that producer
going down at key points for your business.
The next thing I want you to dig on is that the changes we've made to the flow
of how software development happens all the way from idea
through to work in software in production, and actually one is set further.
So I'm talking from now on
about like an existing product with real users with real data.
So we're not talking about
like an existing like greenfield like prompts prompt off you go.
And it's got users. So we have product management.
We have ideas.
Anyone can have ideas in the company about how we evolve the software.
We have product ownerships.
That's coming up with a concrete plan for turning those ideas into taking what
we've got and modifying it and ending up with a hopefully a coherent product.
We've got people who build it actually go off and execute it
with all the new tools, and often the step which is forgotten about,
which is driving adoption and evaluating whether the idea was actually a good idea.
Right.
Because every time we change our product, our digital product, it's an experiment.
And there's no point doing experiments if you don't actually look at the result
and then learn from it.
So all of this should feed back into that process.
And that is the amazing thing about agent development, because some feedback
can be actioned right away.
And if you have a good path to production for deploying the software
as your users are starting to adopt it if you're sat with them, perhaps
if you're at a client, you can actually just change the software
in real time and have it deployed through to your path to production.
And one thing that we noticed is the different stages
of that path to production had different speed ups from AI.
So this is just our experience. Yours might be different.
The building is where the order of magnitude has gone up, right?
If you give a senior software engineer like the time to just build features,
they can build as many features as you want
right now, there might not be the right features.
If we go to the product management, product ownership, we heavily use
AI there to to do product market research,
research, to analyze user feedback, to build roadmaps, to refine issues.
But there's a lot of decisions to be made there.
There's a huge number of decisions.
It's much more important to decide what we're building, in what order.
And that is not something I delegate.
So that's why we haven't found.
We've got the same speed up as we did in building and this one for a while.
It's actually got harder, right?
Because we're providing
too many features to our clients sometimes in a great problem to have, isn't it?
Which can make adoption harder
because we keep dropping new features before the previous ones.
So I think look for friction in your process
is caused by different levels of acceleration,
and you work out what your, your flow of software development is.
And one kind of tip that we've recently executed on is to have software
engineers be directly responsible for adoption of the features they build.
Do not let them just go and build the next feature,
because you end up with lots of features, which is essentially useless.
And if you don't do something like this, or you don't speed up product management
in the same way as you do building, you have to expect software engineers
to build features that you do not need because it's fun, right?
AI system development is fun, and the friction for an idea
turning into working software has gone down,
so we often end up with features that we don't want.
So the way I think about it right now and how the software engineers work in, in
my team is that we've merged together
the friction of getting adoption with the building.
Right.
So engineers aren't allowed to go and build the next feature
until they've done everything they possibly could
to get that feature adopted.
And I come from a like a software development background that became
a platform engineer, and I really believe in the cultural side of DevOps.
And you build it, you run it with something which
I would have said for many, many years and I really believe believed in.
But for now, it's like you build it, you run it,
and you have to drive the adoption of that feature.
Otherwise you just end up with too many features, unused features in production.
I'm now going to dive
a little bit deeper into how the role of our software engineers have changed
over the last year, and I'm going to break down what they do
into three, into three, into roughly three steps.
So we're now just in the build box of the previous diagram.
So technical planning is the first part of actually building a feature.
Architectural decisions testing strategy
how to integrate with third party and dependencies.
That's where you're using a lot of your brain a brain.
As a software engineer.
It's absolutely the thing we put into ADR, as I talked about at the start.
Then we come to execute on said plan.
And obviously that's a bit that's got extremely good with AI.
So code, code, code what needs to be nice and relaxing.
And then we refine.
And for me the refinement is where the magic is up with AI,
because we can quickly iterate on our ideas based on user feedback.
If people don't use things like superpowers, I would highly recommend it.
That's the one that we use is obviously spec
driven frameworks that
people use, but this kind of matches the brainstorming
would be the technical planning, but don't delegate to it.
It's going to ask you lots of questions.
It's going to make you feel very informed,
but it's up to you to come up and take the right technical design.
And then obviously the writing and executing plans,
if you haven't, if you haven't broken your software development flow into that.
So one of the key changes in how an engineer spend
my time is previously, I'd have spent a short amount of time doing
technical planning, quite a long time relaxing with my cup of coffee coding.
I found that quite therapeutic.
And then doing that validate and deploy.
And most people feel like a superhero initially, right?
Super powers is a very apt name because I can go so fast with AI
at the same time as anyone.
Find AI in frustratingly slow, right?
I've come up with the design. I've told you how to implement it.
Why does it take 30 minutes for you to go and like do that 4000 line change?
Come on AI, so what do we actually do?
Everyone's probably gone and done this.
That's my flow. I've compressed the coding.
So what do we do once we've done the first technical planning.
Any guesses?
Yeah we start another one.
Good good good answer.
And then we start another one. Right.
And we all ended up very very tired.
So parallelism is definitely necessary in our engineering humbug.
We actually like almost Monday to everyone in my company is assigned
multiple tasks at the same time.
But we have to be careful about it because what we found happened
is if, let's say people had three complex tasks to do, like three features
which required the brain to think about the system architecture.
The first one would be fantastic.
The second one would be not so good.
By the time you got to the third one, it would be a load of rubbish.
So even though we hadn't delegated our systems thinking to AI,
we've already used the brain, so it's going to come out a bit rubbish.
So one of our kind of guiding principles is to work in parallel.
Absolutely.
But only work on one complex task at a time.
And we assign to label issues and things and say, yeah,
you can pick up these to let go while the agent is doing something else.
Everything I've said so far is about the individual, right?
But I'd say the hardest part of this are a new way of building software
is how to get a team to work together to solve problems with AI.
And I do think you need a team.
As in, I want a team of people that can operate and evolve and maintain
like my digital product.
I don't want one hero.
I don't want some AI system that's not accountable.
I want them to use AI as much as possible to build it.
But you know, people are the should be accountable and have like the real agency.
So I'm sure a lot of people have heard of like the Amazon's
two pizza team keep team sizes down to like 6 to 8.
Absolutely ludicrous idea as far as I was concerned, because
obviously if you've got eight people, you need eight pizzas to feed them.
It's definitely two.
I think American pizzas are bigger than us anyway.
Let's assume you can feed to a team with two pizzas, right?
If you don't think about it, what's going to happen? Is this right?
Everyone's going to be addicted to their new game,
which is, like I said, development.
They're going to prompt, prompt and what's going to happen.
Lots of pull requests, 48 pull requests.
And then someone is going to tell you that the most common complaint in
AI software, ISIS's software development is what is it?
Reviews of the bottleneck.
This is crazy. I think this is crazy, right?
Because we're complaining that we can build
so much valuable software that we don't have the time to look at it.
And we've spent a couple of decades inventing practices
to build a shared understanding of a system and maintain it.
Right.
We're talking about XP pairing more being boomerangs.
We did all this stuff with the goal of not having no knowledge side of it.
Right? I think this helps, right?
Because if you put the friction of adoption directly to the engineers,
they don't build
quite as much stuff in parallel, which is a good thing,
because what you want is the outcome of the use of the software,
not just features in production.
And like this is like I've gone through like most of the engineers I work with.
And you cannot get yourself worth from the features you prompt.
This is not a new problem with AI.
We've always struggled with people. Want to tip it up the code?
Get the commitment GitHub rather than review other people's stuff.
But it's massively accelerated by AI as a as a bigger problem anyway.
So what have we done about it?
So rather than having our normal steam
sizes of 6 to 8 people, we've made them much, much smaller.
So they're now two utmost four.
And we give them a mission.
And their mission is based on adopted software by particular customers.
And you're not allowed to start the next feature
unless you've done everything in your power.
So if we're at a stand
up and you're telling me how great the next feature you're building is,
if you haven't spoken to that customer about getting them
to use the previous feature, that's not something we do anymore.
Which then means that that small sub stream needs to do the reviewing.
Fix the bugs, gathering the user feedback.
The most important part of this though, is if we break that team of 6 to 8 people
into sub streams of two of 2 to 4 is you get three pizzas,
because obviously you can't have a two different substitute share pizzas.
The problem this produces, which is the same problem that we had
when we broke up, bigger teams like we broke up
bigger teams into teams of 6 to 8 is they can go off in different directions.
They've got a mission, they've got focus. That's fantastic.
So you really need to think about how you're going to do
product ownership across these different streams,
let them work in isolation and let them just review their own stuff,
but make sure that key architectural decisions
are still reviewed by the right people, and make sure there's at least 1
or 2 people who are working across the streams
and understand how everything's going to work together.
So a question I keep asking myself through all of this
transformation is, has AI changed good engineering practices?
And, you know, this is a graph I've completely made up with no real data.
But we start off with high velocity and then we get slower
and then we fix some stuff and then we get slower and then we fix some stuff,
then we get slower, and then maybe we end up somewhere below what we started.
Right?
So we start off conquering the world,
and then eventually we end up at some some steady pace for a digital product.
So what causes this? Well, there's two answers. There's technical debt.
That's the obvious one. And the other one is success.
Obviously, success is not necessarily a bad thing.
When I say technical debt, it's things like longer
testing cycles, more dependencies, harder to make code changes.
And obviously agents will have the same problems
that humans have for modifying a code base in a safe way.
Success is going to be things like more customers, more deployments,
larger data sets.
So there's certain engineering practices which I think are even more important.
I've got more than I can cover in this talk, but I'm just going to cover
a couple probably.
Wonderful that I've got time for one minute.
There you go.
One the first is system architecture really matters.
I already talked about this, but why do we break things up
into loosely coupled services?
Maybe a very important word. Loosely coupled.
Otherwise you've just got a distributed mess, right?
It's for fast feedback cycles.
If we're going to build more features, we're going to end up with larger systems.
I'm talking about complex systems rather than just like,
say, trivial web,
but it is imperative that we keep the feedback of each of those components
very short.
It's 15 minutes for me, is absolute maximum for running a full suite of tests,
which gives me a high level of confidence that that thing works.
The other thing is,
if we're going to modify software more quickly, blast radius really matters.
What is the worst thing that can go wrong
when one instance of a pipeline path to production happens?
So and only really way to do that is to design your systems
so that if one of these components goes down, most of your product functionality
still works.
And I was going to go through an example of the types of tests we used.
But I'm not going to have time but feel talk to me after if you want to.
So I'm going to end on time
with a few final thoughts, which is define your principles for using AI.
And by that I mean the stuff at the start.
Decide what you want humans to understand versus agents decide
like what dependency or vendor lock in you're happy with.
Identify your real bottleneck all the way from idea to adoption.
Do not get sucked in by vanity metrics that measure one little bit in the middle,
like token usage or commits or PR merged.
There has to be a features in production is what I used to use before AI.
That's not good enough anymore.
You have toes, features actually have to be used
and you have to expose those to your engineers.
Or certainly that's what what we're trying to find your definition of good
in a very concrete way, and then have AI to be held accountable to it.
I'm turning this talk into a few articles for our website.
If you want us to send you them.
There's a QR code there because we love QR codes these days.
They made a real comeback.
And thank you very much for taking the time to listen.
Christopher,